Tour #1.*5 Day Sri Lanka Highlights Tour*  Perfect if it’s your first time + you’re flying in/out of Colombo. Mix of culture, nature, tea, and beach.*Day 1: Colombo → Sigiriya/Dambulla*  - Morning: Pick up from Colombo, drive 4-5 hrs to Cultural Triangle- Afternoon: Dambulla Cave Temple - huge Buddha statues + cave paintings- Evening: Check in near Sigiriya, relax. Sunset view from Pidurangala if you’ve got energy- *Stay*: Sigiriya/Dambulla area*Day 2: Sigiriya → Kandy*  - Early morning: Climb Sigiriya Rock Fortress. 1200 steps but the view + frescoes are worth it- Afternoon: Drive 3 hrs to Kandy. Visit Temple of the Sacred Tooth Relic- Evening: Kandy Lake walk + cultural dance show- *Stay*: Kandy*Day 3: Kandy → Nuwara Eliya*  - Morning: Peradeniya Botanical Gardens + Ceylon tea tasting- Afternoon: Drive to “Little England” Nuwara Eliya. - Evening: Gregory Lake + cold mountain air- *Stay*: Nuwara Eliya*Day 4: Nuwara Eliya → Ella → Mirissa/Galle*  - Morning drive to Ella visit Nine Arch Bridge for that classic train shot (depening on train time)- Afternoon: Long drive 5-6 hrs down to south coast. Galle Fort if you stop there- Evening: Hit the beach at Mirissa/Unawatuna, seafood dinner- *Stay*: Mirissa or Unawatuna*Day 5: South Coast → Colombo*  - Morning: Turtle hatchery in Kosgoda or whale watching in Mirissa if it’s season Dec-Apr- Afternoon: Drive back to Colombo 2.5-3 hrs. Last min shopping at Dutch Hospital or Pettah Market- Evening: Fly out / end tour*Note: This is just a guideline only, and we will assist you to your organise  your trip according to your requirements.Tour ＃27-day cultural tour of Sri Lanka — hits the big heritage spots without rushing you:*Day 1: Colombo / Negambo → Sigiriya*  - Arrive, drive to Cultural Triangle ∼4hrs  - Afternoon Evening: Minneriya or Echo Park  (watch elephannt gathering) + traditional dinner in Habarana ,  *Stay*: Sigiriya/Habarana area*Day 2: Sigiriya & Dambulla*  - Sunrise climb Sigiriya Rock Fortress - UNESCO site, ancient palace + frescoes  - Afternoon: Dambulla Cave Temple with 150+ Buddha statues  *Stay*: Sigiriya/ Habarana*Day 3: Polonnaruwa*  - Full day cycling/exploring ancient city ruins - Royal Palace, Gal Vihara Buddha statues  - Evening: Back to Sigiriya/ Habarana  Aurweda Spa (relax) *Stay*: Sigiriya/ Habarana*Day 4: Kandy*  - Drive 3.5hrs via spice garden in Matale  - Visit Temple of the Sacred Tooth Relic  - Evening: Kandy cultural dance show , enjoy a walk along the Kandy lake *Stay*: Kandy*Day 5: Kandy → Nuwara Eliya*  - Morning: Royal Botanical Gardens, Peradeniya  - Tea factory tour + tasting  *Stay*: Nuwara Eliya "Little England"*Day 6: Nuwara Eliya → Ella*  - Morning: Horton Plains + World’s End viewpoint if you’re up early  - Drive to Ella 1.5hrs  - Sunset at Nine Arch Bridge  *Stay*: Ella*Day 7: Ella → Galle*  - Morning: Little Adam’s Peak hike 45min  - Drive 4hrs to Galle Fort - Dutch colonial UNESCO fort, churches, museums  - Evening drop to Colombo airport, ∼2hrs from Galle (End of tour)*Note: This is just a guideline only, and we will assist you to your organise  your trip according to your requirements.Tour # 310-day Sri Lanka cultural tour to Jaffna + the north to the classic triangle:*Day 1: Colombo/ Negambo → Anuradhapura*  - Arrive, drive 4hrs north  - Evening: Sacred Bodhi Tree + Ruwanwelisaya stupa  + Isurumuniya Temple *Stay*: Anuradhapura*Day 2: Anuradhapura → Jaffna*  - Morning: Drive/ train 3.5hrs to Jaffna  - Evening: Jaffna Library, Jaffna Clock Tower, Nallur Kovil temple + Jaffna Fort at sunset  *Stay*: Jaffna*Day 3: Jaffna Peninsula*  - Morning Nagadeepa Viharaya  + Nagapusariamman Kovil Temple- Afternoon: Dambakolapatuna, Keerimalai hot springs, Bottemless wel, Kadurigoda Temple- Try Jaffna crab curry for dinner  (optional)*Stay*: Jaffna*Day 4: Jaffna → Sigiriya*  - Morning drive /train back south ∼5hrs  - Evening: Village safari + cultural show in Habarana  *Stay*: Habarana / Sigiriya*Day 5: Habarana/ Sigiriya & Dambulla*  - Sunrise climb Sigiriya Rock Fortress  - Afternoon: Dambulla Cave Temple  *Stay*: Habarana/ Sigiriya*Day 6: Habarana/ Sigiriya → Kandy*  - Morning: Cycle ancient city ruins of Polonnaruwa  - Drive 3hrs to Kandy via Matale spice garden  - Evening: Temple of the Sacred Tooth Relic + Kandyan dance show  *Stay*: Kandy*Day 7: Kandy → Nuwara Eliya*  - Morning: Peradeniya Botanical Gardens  - Tea factory tour + tasting  *Stay*: Nuwara Eliya*Day 8: Nuwara Eliya → Ella*  - Early: Horton Plains + World’s End if you want the hike  - Drive 1.5hrs to Ella  - Sunset at Nine Arch Bridge  *Stay*: Ella*Day 9: Ella → Galle*  - Morning: Udawalawa National Park (elephants)   - Drive to Galle Fort for extra colonial vibes  - Stay in  Galle *Day 10: Galle → Colombo/ Airport* - Maduriver, turtle hatchery- Colombo city tour and shopping (as time permits)- Depart (End of tour)*Note: This is just a guideline only, and we will assist you to your organise  your trip according to your requirements.Tour ＃48-day Sri Lanka cultural + beach tour with Trincomalee:*Day 1: Colombo → Sigiriya*  - Arrive, drive 4hrs to Cultural Triangle  - Evening: Village safari + traditional dinner  *Stay*: Sigiriya/Habarana*Day 2: Sigiriya & Dambulla*  - Sunrise climb Sigiriya Rock Fortress - palace ruins + frescoes  - Afternoon: Dambulla Cave Temple, 5 caves full of Buddha statues  *Stay*: Sigiriya / Dambulla*Day 3: Polonnaruwa → Trincomalee*  - Morning: Cycle ancient city ruins of Polonnaruwa - Gal Vihara statues are iconic  - Drive 2.5hrs to Trinco  - Evening: Sunset at Marble Beach  *Stay*: Trincomalee*Day 4: Trincomalee*  - Morning: Koneswaram Temple "Temple of a Thousand Pillars" on Swami Rock  - Afternoon: snorkel at Pigeon Island  *Stay*: Trincomalee*Day 5: Trincomalee → Kandy*  - Drive 4hrs via Matale spice garden  - Evening: Temple of the Sacred Tooth Relic + Kandyan dance show  *Stay*: Kandy*Day 6: Kandy → Nuwara Eliya*  - Morning: Peradeniya Royal Botanical Gardens  - Drive to Nuwara Eliya  through tea estate- Tea factory tour + tasting  *Stay*: Nuwara Eliya*Day 7: Nuwara Eliya → Ella*  - Morning Nuwara Eliya city toour- Drive 1.5hrs to Ella  - Sunset at Nine Arch Bridge  *Stay*: Ella*Day 8: Ella → Colombo/Galle*  - Morning: Little Adam’s Peak hike 45min  or drive to Galle- Drive to Galle Fort for Dutch colonial streets,  stilt fishermen, turtle hatchery- Drive to  Colombo  / Airport- Depart (End of tour)*Note: This is just a guideline only, and we will assist you to your organise  your trip according to your requirements.Tour #5*7-Day Culture + Wildlife Tour Sri Lanka**Day 1: Colombo → Negombo*  Arrive, relax at beach. Visit St. Mary’s Church + fish market. Overnight Negombo.*Day 2: Negombo → Sigiriya*  Drive 4hrs. Climb Sigiriya Rock Fortress “Lion Rock” + see 5th century frescoes. Sunset view. Overnight Sigiriya.*Day 3: Polonnaruwa + Minneriya Safari*  Morning: Explore ancient city of Polonnaruwa - UNESCO ruins, Gal Vihara Buddha statues.  Evening: Minneriya safari for “The Gathering” of elephants Jul-Sep. Other months = Kaudulla. Overnight Sigiriya.*Day 4: Sigiriya → Kandy*  Stop at Dambulla Cave Temple on way. Afternoon: Kandy city tour + Temple of Sacred Tooth Relic. Cultural dance show in evening. Overnight Kandy.*Day 5: Kandy → Yala*  Morning train to Ella for tea plantation views, or direct drive 6hrs to Yala. Evening safari: Leopards, elephants, crocs. Overnight Yala.*Day 6: Yala Full Day Safari*  Early morning + evening game drives. Yala has highest leopard density in the world. Also sloth bears, jackals, 200+ birds. Overnight Yala.*Day 7: Yala → Galle → Colombo*  Drive via Galle. Stop at Galle Fort Dutch colonial town + lighthouse. Continue to Colombo for departure/flight. (End of tour)*Note: This is just a guideline only, and we will assist you to your organise your trip according to your requirements.Tour #606DAYS / 05 NIGHTS		Day 1:	COLOMBO – AIRPORT – NEGOMBO / COLOMBO 	Stay over night in Negambo or Colombo.Day 2: 	NEGOMBO/ COLOMBO TO PINNAWALA - MINNERIYA - DAMBULLA.	Visit Negambo city (the fish market, and church)	And Then move  to Pinnawala Elephant orphanage. and have lunch in a local resturant.	In the afternoon transfer from Pinnawala to Minneriya and visit Minneriya National Park. .	Dinner and overnight stay in DAMBULLA	 Day 3:	DAMBULLA  SIGIRIYA  PERADENIYA- KANDY 	Have breakfast and transfer from Dambulla to Sigiriya to visit Sigiriya Lion Rock.  	In the afternoon transfer from Sigiriya to Peradeniya			  Lunch in Dambulla / Kandy depend on time		      Visit Peradeniya Botanical garden		      Dinner and Over night stay in Kandy. Day 4:	KANDY -TEA PLANTATION - NUWARA ELIYA	After breakfast City tour in Kandy/ visit Temple  of tooth relics		      Visit a tea plantation and a tea factory			Lunch at a resturant on the way.			Transfer to Nuwara Eliya			City tour in Nuwara Eliya (red post-office,Gregory Lake, fruit market and 			shoping)			Dinner and overnight stay in Nuwara Eliya	Day 5:	NUWARA ELIYA – HORTAIN PLAINS - BANDARAWELA - ELLA - TISSAMAHARAMAYA	Breakfast packets and leave early morning to visit Horton Plains	Then trans for to Ella	Lunch at a resturant on the way depending on the time. 	Transfer to Ella 	Visit nine arch bridge 	and proceed to Tissamaharama 	Dinner and Overnight Stay in Tissamaharama			  Transfer to Tissamaharama to Yala with packet breakfast.	Then transfer from Yala to Koggala			  Visit Stilt Fishermen  (optional)			  Transfer from Koggala to Galle			  Visit Galle Fourt			  Over night stay in Galle / Ahungalla/ Beruwala. Day 6 :	GALLE/ AHUNGALLA/ BERUWALA COLOMBO -AIRPORT 	Breakfast at Cinnamon Bey	Transfer from hotel to Airport  via Colombo (depending on flight time.)Transfer from Colombo to Airport for departureEnd of the tour
